Liam McCormack

Junior Software Engineer

Email - <u>liammccormack@outlook.com</u>

LinkedIn - www.linkedin.com/in/liam-mccormack-3024171aa/

Website - www.liammccormack.com

Having worked in the TV industry for a number of years, I decided to switch out the dark camera studios for the comfort and warmth of a computer screen. I will soon be graduating from the coding bootcamp 'Northcoders' and be ready to take my first steps into the world of tech. I'm a highly motivated self-starter, a huge team player and I'm more than willing to take on new challenges, learn new programming languages and become a more fluent object oriented programmer. You can find out more about me on my website!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript

Front End: React, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap
Back End: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, Knex, Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Coding Bootcamp Student

Northcoders (Sept 2020 - Jan 2021)

- 14 week coding course learning full-stack software development, working entirely remote
- Primarily developed in JavaScript, working on both Back-end and Front-end features
- For Back-end I built a Rest API using Express to set up a server, Knex to connect to a database and deployed a database using Heroku. To run code I made use of Node.js and asynchronous programming
- For Front-end I will be building an app using the front-end framework React
- During the course, we took an agile approach with two or three weekly sprints. I would carry out pair programming often, and switch partners twice a week
- Following industry best practices including Test-Driven Development, I used Jest testing framework to write unit tests and integration tests
- Used the version-control system Git to commit and push onto course and personal projects on a daily basis
- During my time on the course, I became highly familiar with collaborative tools and features such as Slack and Zoom

Casting Researcher

ITV (May 2018 - Feb 2020)

- Developed and helped generate new TV programme ideas
- Created reports and briefs for meetings with other members of the production team
- Sourced and researched facts, figures and information using the internet
- Directed a small number of shoots and carried out editing for broadcast

Between 2015-2018, I also worked in various roles for BBC and Wagamamas.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio - www.liammccormack.com

My own personal website built using HTML/CSS/JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap.

Github - https://github.com/Liam-McCormack/Portfolio-Website

Witcher Bestiary Fansite - https://eloquent-lovelace-360d57.netlify.app/

I was inspired to create a web browser project based on the in-game bestiary guide in the popular video game 'The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt'. Built using **HTML/CSS/JavaScript** and **jQuery**.

Github - https://github.com/Liam-McCormack/Witcher-Bestiary-v2

EDUCATION

University of Salford

09/2012 - 05/2015

BA Degree - 2:1 Television and Radio **Burnley College** 09/2010 - 06/2012

3 A Levels - BBB Media, Film, Media & Communications

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

In my spare time, I also enjoy:

- Going for long countryside walks with my partner and French Bulldog
- Going to the gym
- Making and drinking a strong builder's cup of tea
- Playing video games on both console and PC